BHAVYA P

Kasaragod, India 671317 | 9497551175 | bhavyabala29@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Recent graduate with foundational knowledge in chemistry and hands-on experience gained through academic projects and internships. Demonstrates strong teamwork, problem-solving, and time-management skills. Prepared to start career and make meaningful contributions with commitment and drive.

Professional Experience

Intern

07/2024 to 10/2024

Merck – Bangalore, India

Worked in Research and Development department

Intern Syngene International limited – Bangalore, India

06/2023 to 08/2023

Completed internship project titled 'Reduction of acids to alcohols' under the guidance of Mrs Prajwal Mathias.

- Improved Knowledge in keeping and monitoring of various organic reaction.
- Improved skills in performing column chromatography, thin layer chromatography.
- Knowledge in various named reactions.

Education

Msc Chemistry 05/2024

St Agnes College Centre For Post Graduate Studies And Research- Mangaluru, Karnataka CGPA: 7.92

Bsc (Botany, Zoology, Chemistry)

08/2022

St Agnes College (Autonomous)- Mangaluru, Karnataka

CGPA: 8.90

HSE 03/2019

Chattanchal Higher Secondary School- Kasaragod, Kerala

Percentage: 92

SSLC 03/2017

Chattanchal Higher Secondary School- Kasaragod, Kerala

Percentage: 96

Training

- Hydroponics, One day workshop, St Agnes College (Autonomous)
- Hands on training on drug discovery & formulation development using R&D instruments / equipment, One week workshop program, National Institute of Technology Warangal
- Organics in Flexitronics, Seminar, Department of PG Chemistry, St Agnes College Mangalore
- Challenges and opportunities in the global chemistry enterprise, National level seminar, St. Aloysius College

Projects

Phytochemical Screening and Analytical Techniques of Neem Tulsi Ficus

Plants are the main source of medicine in our day to day life. Analyzing the constituents and medicinal aspects of the leaf part will be a better step towards future scenario.

Green Synthesis of Functionalised Carbon Nanodots using Biomass as Corrosion Inhibitor

Paperpresentations

• Exploring the efficacy of Fe3O4 nanoparticles in mitigating corrosion of maraging steel in acidic environment, Two day international conference, Srinivas Institute of Technology

Certifications

- Cosmetic Chemistry, St Agnes College (Autonomous), 30 hours
- Research methodology in chemical science, St Agnes College (Autonomous), 30 hours
- NPTEL course on analytical chemistry

Achievements and Awards

- Students police cadet district level best cadet, 2014-16
- Student police cadet state-level leaders summit, 2014-16, Won state level best diary writer award.
- Christina Alapat Achievement Award, For the best outgoing student in Botany.
- Second prize in start-up spank, Organised by department of management and entrepreneurship at St Agnes College Mangalore.
- •Riya Mathias Achievement Award, For the best outgoing student in Chemistry 2024.

References

Dr Sapna Kumari M, Head of the department of chemistry
St Agnes College for Post Graduate studies and research, Mangalore, Karnataka
sapna@stagnescollege.edu.in